<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Aural Skills I]]></title>
  <link href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-30T12:00:20-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kris Shaffer]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[kris.shaffer@colorado.edu]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meeting 3 info]]></title>
    <link href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/08/meeting-3-info/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-30T11:40:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/08/meeting-3-info</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Please bring manuscript paper, a pencil, and an eraser to class on Wednesday, Sept. 4. You will not need Kazez or Berkowitz. Our focus will be on listening and recognition.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meeting 2 assignment]]></title>
    <link href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/08/meeting-2-assignment/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-27T14:02:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/08/meeting-2-assignment</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For <em>Tuesday, Sept. 3, 8am</em>, please do the following:</p>

<ul>
<li>Read this very short resource on <a href="http://kris.shaffermusic.com/musicianship/meter.html">Meter and time signatures</a>. (It should be review for most of you.)</li>
<li>Record a video of yourself performing all seven <a href="http://kris.shaffermusic.com/musicianship/melodicSequentials.html">major-key melodic sequentials</a>. Upload to Google Drive, and share with me. (Feel free to record each sequential one at a time and either splice the videos together or upload multiple files into a single folder, if necessary.)</li>
<li>Record a video of yourself performing rhythmic exercise no. 28 (on p. 21) from the Kazez, with appropriate rhythmic syllables. Upload to GDrive, and share with me.</li>
<li>Also make a 1–2 minute video introducing yourself: Who are you? Where are you from? What are your goals? (in life, and in this class) This will help me get to know you better.</li>
</ul>


<p>A 1-minute video domonstrating uploading and sharing files on Google Drive can be found <a href="http://kris.shaffermusic.com/musicianship/GDrive.html">here</a>. If you have any difficulties, please make use of Piazza to ask questions of me and/or your classmates. CU officially supports GDrive, so the student help desk should also be able to help.</p>

<p>Have a great Labor Day weekend! (In order to enjoy it fully, I highly recommend you complete as much of this assignment as possible by Friday.)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meeting 1 assignment]]></title>
    <link href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/08/meeting-1-assignment/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-24T19:56:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/08/meeting-1-assignment</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In advance of our next meeting (Wednesday, Aug. 28), practice the <a href="http://kris.shaffermusic.com/musicianship/melodicSequentials.html">major-key melodic sequentials</a> introduced in class. (There will be a video performance of these sequentials, along with some rhythmic exercises, due on Sept. 3.)</p>

<p>Sign up for <a href="http://www.spotify.com">Spotify</a>, <a href="http://www.learningcatalytics.com">Learning Catalytics</a>, and <a href="http://www.piazza.com">Piazza</a> (if you haven&#8217;t already).</p>

<p>Please make use of Piazza, rather than emailing me directly, if you have any questions about the course, the syllabus, the policies, the homework, or the technology.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[For Monday, August 26 (first meeting)]]></title>
    <link href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/08/for-monday/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-22T11:06:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/08/for-monday</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome (back) to Boulder!</p>

<p>Before our first meeting, please read the <a href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/syllabus/">syllabus</a> and <a href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/policies/">policies</a> pages for this course, as well as the <a href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/units/unit1.html">Unit I guide</a>. Note any questions you have about these documents.</p>

<p>Also, please bring a web-enabled device to class—such as a smartphone, tablet, or laptop—and your copy of Kazez, <em>Rhythm Reading</em>, and Berkowitz, <em>A New Approach to Sight Singing</em>.</p>

<p>I look forward to meeting all of you on Monday!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Piazza]]></title>
    <link href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/08/piazza/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-22T10:22:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/08/piazza</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This term we will be using Piazza for class discussion. The system is highly catered to getting you help fast and efficiently from classmates and myself. Rather than emailing questions about course materials directly to me, I encourage you to post your questions on Piazza. If you have any problems or feedback for the developers, email <a href="mailto:team@piazza.com">team@piazza.com</a>.</p>

<p>Of course, matters of a private nature should <em>not</em> be addressed on Piazza. Please email me about private concerns, or better yet, come by my office so we can discuss them in person.</p>

<p>Find our class Piazza page at: <a href="https://piazza.com/colorado/fall2013/musc1121001/home">https://piazza.com/colorado/fall2013/musc1121001/home</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
