<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Aural Skills I]]></title>
  <link href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-02T11:43:11-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kris Shaffer]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[kris.shaffer@colorado.edu]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prep for Dec. 4]]></title>
    <link href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/11/prep-for-dec-4/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-22T13:40:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/11/prep-for-dec-4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Before Wednesday&#8217;s class, please revise any performance videos that need it. Everyone should be passing all of the prepared performance categories by Wednesday.</p>

<p>Please bring staff paper and Berkowitz to class on Wednesday.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Performance videos for Fri., Nov. 22]]></title>
    <link href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/11/performance-videos-for-fri/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-19T11:29:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/11/performance-videos-for-fri</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>All prepared performance videos are due <strong>8am, Friday, Nov. 22</strong>. The only new ones should be the Cycle 4 materials (see the <a href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/assessment/">Assessment</a> guide for links) if you have kept up with the homework assignments.</p>

<p>There is no required prep work for after break (Dec. 2), but keep an eye on this website and your email for instructions on what to bring to class.</p>

<p>Have a great break!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prep for Nov. 20]]></title>
    <link href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/11/prep-for-nov-20/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-14T11:15:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/11/prep-for-nov-20</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For class on Nov. 20, go to the <strong>MUSC 1121 shared materials</strong> in Google Drive and open the folder called <strong>Introduction to bass-line dictation</strong>. For each recording, transcribe the bass line (key and meter listed below), put an asterisk above each bass note that is accompanied by a full block chord, and label the cadence type (PAC, IAC, or HC) at the end of each excerpt. Bring these transcriptions to class for discussion and troubleshooting.</p>

<p>Excerpt 36.1: Tonic of A, 6/4.</p>

<p>Excerpt 36.2: Tonic of E-flat, 3/2.</p>

<p>Excerpt 36.3: Tonic of C, 2/4.</p>

<p>Excerpt 36.4: Tonic of B-flat, 2/2.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prep for Nov. 13 & 18]]></title>
    <link href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/11/prep-for-nov-18/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-08T10:17:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/11/prep-for-nov-18</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Please bring Kazez, Berkowitz, your keyboard schemata packet, and staff paper to class on Nov. 13.</p>

<p>I have posted the materials for the <em>keyboard prepared performance</em> video portfolio. Please <a href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/media/keyboardExercises.pdf">download the exercises</a>, and record a video of yourself performing each one perfectly or nearly so. Create a folder on Google Drive named &#8220;LASTNAME Keyboard Performance Portfolio&#8221;, upload these videos to that folder, and share the folder with me <strong>by class time on Nov. 18</strong>. If they are up to standard, this will complete your <em>keyboard prepared performance</em> <a href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/assessment/">course objective</a>. If not, you will need to reqork them and resubmit them.</p>

<p>I have also posted the Cycle 4 singing materials, linked from the <a href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/assessment/">assessment page</a> under the appropriate categories. If you are comfortable doing so (it is not required yet), you may make videos of those rhythms and melodies to add to your Cycle 3 materials. Once your Cycle 3 and 4 melodies and rhythms are recorded as performed (nearly) flawlessly, you will complete your <em>melodic prepared performance</em> and <em>rhythmic prepared performance</em> objectives. The goal will be for everyone to meet the prepared performance objectives before Thanksgiving break, so that we can focus entirely on listening and sight-reading during the last two weeks of class. Feel free to work ahead as you are able.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prep for Nov. 11]]></title>
    <link href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/11/prep-for-nov-11/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-05T13:33:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/11/prep-for-nov-11</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For Monday&#8217;s class, read the new resource on <a href="http://kris.shaffermusic.com/musicianship/protonotation.html">protonotation</a>. Then find an 8–12 measure passage of music that is 1) in compound meter and 2) in minor with some raised <em>la</em>s and <em>ti</em>s. Rewrite that melody in protonotation and bring both the original and the protonotation transcription to class.</p>

<p>Bring Kazez and Berkowitz to class on Monday.</p>

<p>If you had difficulty recognizing the keyboard schemata in class, spend some additional time before Monday playing through them and memorizing the sound of each schema.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prep for Nov. 6]]></title>
    <link href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/10/prep-for-nov-6/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-29T09:04:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/10/prep-for-nov-6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For Wednesday&#8217;s class, play through the <a href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/media/KBschemata-practiceHandout.pdf">Keyboard voice-leading schemata</a> distributed in class. As you play, try to &#8220;chunk&#8221; these schemata; that is, try to get to the point where you can recognize them as individual patterns, rather than two or three differerent chords put together.</p>

<p>As you play, also try to come up with an explanation for the names assigned to each schema or set of schemata.</p>

<p>Bring the schemata handout and staff paper to class on Wednesday. You will not need Berkowitz or Kazez.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Week 10 prep and assignment]]></title>
    <link href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/10/week-10-prep-and-assignment/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-25T13:48:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/10/week-10-prep-and-assignment</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I will be away on Wednesday for a conference. During class time on Wednesday, please get together and either as a whole group or in multiple smaller groups, work on the following assignment. At the end of class, please write a 1–2 sentence email to me explaining what you did/accomplished during class time.</p>

<p>Assignment due <em>Monday, Nov. 4, 8am</em>:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Choose three of the following rhythmic exercises from Kazez: nos. 70, 73, 76, 83, or 88.</p></li>
<li><p>Choose three of the five melodies on the <a href="media/rec3.pdf">Recitation 3 guide</a>.</p></li>
<li><p>Practice them until you have mastered them, and record a video of yourself performing each of the six exercises flawlessly, or nearly so.</p></li>
<li><p>Create a new folder in Google Drive, upload your videos (clearly labeled in the file name) to that folder, and share it with me before Monday&#8217;s class.</p></li>
<li><p>Bring Berkowitz, Kazez, and staff paper to class on Monday.</p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cadence playlist analysis]]></title>
    <link href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/10/cadence-playlist-analysis/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-15T15:15:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/10/cadence-playlist-analysis</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Following are the first cadences in each piece of the assigned playlist. If you have any questions, please ask in class or on Piazza.</p>

<p>1) K. 452: 0:27 HC</p>

<p>2) Haydn 105: 0:07 IAC</p>

<p>3) Haydn 89: 0:04 IAC</p>

<p>4) Haydn 105: 0:07 HC</p>

<p>5) K. 283 0:13 PAC</p>

<p>6) K. 545, I.: 0:18 HC</p>

<p>7) K. 545, III.: 0:05 HC</p>

<p>8) K. 550: 0:10 IAC</p>

<p>9) K. 551: 0:08 HC</p>

<p>10) K. 385: 0:05 HC</p>

<p>11) Op. 21: 0:05 HC</p>

<p>12) Op. 2/1: 0:09 HC</p>

<p>13) Haydn 45: 0:16 PAC</p>

<p>Note that the first cadence in a classical piece is far more likely to be a half cadence than any other type. (And keep in mind that I made sure to pick examples that included IACs so that you would have some to practice.) Use this knowledge to guide your listening when given examples from the beginnings of pieces.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prep for Oct. 21 &amp; 23 (UPDATE)]]></title>
    <link href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/10/prep-for-oct-21-and-23/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-15T13:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/10/prep-for-oct-21-and-23</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Monday, October 21, is recitation no. 2. Be sure to sign up for a time with a partner and prepare the materials distributed in class.</p>

<p>Wednesday, October 23, will be the listening quiz for Unit II. Recitation preparation will be your best prep for the listening quiz, along with practicing intervals and triads on teoria. I will post additional materials for cadences and dictation practice later in the week.</p>

<p>UPDATE: I have added two-part dictation exercises to the MUSC 1121 Shared Resources folder on Google Drive. See the PDF in that folder for key, meter, and length information.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Asst. for Oct. 15]]></title>
    <link href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/10/asst-for-oct-15/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-10T11:34:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/10/asst-for-oct-15</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For <em>9am, Tuesday, Oct. 15</em>, do <a href="http://www.colorado.edu/music/courses/musc1121/2_2/index.html">Lab 2.2</a>. Drop it by my office or send me a picture/scan of your completed lab by then.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, we will do a little singing and a lot of dictation practice. Bring species and canon exercises to class, along with staff paper and a pencil. You do not need Berkowitz or Kazez.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prep for Oct. 14]]></title>
    <link href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/10/prep-for-oct-14/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-08T11:04:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/10/prep-for-oct-14</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For Monday, October 14, please review the <a href="http://open.spotify.com/user/kris.shaffer/playlist/7H2g6Bv8rN6HwlGolcaL9H">cadence playlist</a> from class. Listen to the first phrase of each track again. For those discussed in class, you know what type of cadences they are; review the sound of those cadences. For those we didn&#8217;t get to, identify the first cadence you hear, write down the timing and the cadence type (HC/PAC/IAC), and bring to class.</p>

<iframe src="https://embed.spotify.com/?uri=spotify:user:kris.shaffer:playlist:7H2g6Bv8rN6HwlGolcaL9H" width="300" height="380" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe>


<p>Also, please bring staff paper, species counterpoint exemplars, and Berkowitz to class on Monday.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Asst &amp; Prep for Oct. 8–9]]></title>
    <link href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/10/asst-and-prep-for-oct-8-slash-9/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-04T14:05:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/10/asst-and-prep-for-oct-8-slash-9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For <em>Tuesday, Oct. 8, 9am</em>, do <a href="http://www.colorado.edu/music/courses/musc1121/2_1/index.html">Lab 2.1</a> (skipping the section on cadences).  Please slide it under my office door (N138) or email me a picture/scan of it by 9am.</p>

<p>Before Wednesday&#8217;s class (Oct. 9), read the resource on <a href="http://kris.shaffermusic.com/musicianship/cadenceTypes.html">Classical cadence types</a>. Don&#8217;t worry about the weird chord notation. For now, when you see <strong>D5</strong>, think <strong>V<sup>(7)</sup></strong>, and when you see <strong>T1</strong>, think <strong>I</strong>.</p>

<p>The playlist from Oct. 7&#8217;s class is <a href="http://open.spotify.com/user/kris.shaffer/playlist/7H2g6Bv8rN6HwlGolcaL9H">here</a>.</p>

<iframe src="https://embed.spotify.com/?uri=spotify:user:kris.shaffer:playlist:7H2g6Bv8rN6HwlGolcaL9H" width="300" height="380" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meeting 11 assignment]]></title>
    <link href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/10/meeting-11-assignment/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-01T12:45:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/10/meeting-11-assignment</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For <em>Friday, Oct. 4, 8am</em>, record a video of yourself singing melody #82 (Berkowitz, p. 21). Prepare and practice it as best you can, using a keyboard if possible, before recording. Don&#8217;t sweat it if it&#8217;s not perfect, but get it as solid as you can.</p>

<p>Bring Berkowitz and plenty of staff paper to class on Monday.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meeting 10 assignment]]></title>
    <link href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/09/meeting-10-assignment/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-27T15:23:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/09/meeting-10-assignment</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>If</em> you did not pass (receive a check mark) on either your interval or triad ID portions of Quiz 1, go to <a href="http://teoria.com">teoria.com</a>, and click on Exercises <a href="https://www.teoria.com/mobile/index.php">&#8220;for mobile devices&#8221;</a>. (Be sure to use the mobile exercises, so you can view/share your score without paying for an account!) Practice <a href="https://www.teoria.com/mobile/intervals/ie.php?l=en">Intervals</a> and/or <a href="https://www.teoria.com/mobile/triads/c3e.php?l=en">Triads</a>, according to what you need to practice. When you think you are up to where you need to be or have made significant progress, take a fresh pass through 10 or so examples, take a screenshot of your result, and send it to me.</p>

<p>Note that if you did not pass those sections on your quiz, <em>this is not an optional assignment</em>. Those who did pass those sections are welcome to do extra practice, of course. Interval and triad ID will be on the Unit II labs and quiz.</p>

<p>Bring Berkowitz and Kazez to class again on Wednesday.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meeting 9 assignment (Sept. 25)]]></title>
    <link href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/09/meeting-9-assignment-sept-25/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-24T09:46:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/09/meeting-9-assignment-sept-25</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>*For Friday, Sept. 27, 8am, please record yourself singing the following <a href="http://kris.shaffermusic.com/musicianship/melodicSequentials.html">melodic sequentials</a> while conducting the appropriate meter:</p>

<ul>
<li>#1 in natural minor</li>
<li>#2 in harmonic minor</li>
<li>#3 in natural minor</li>
<li>#4 in harmonic minor</li>
<li>#7 in natural minor</li>
</ul>


<p><em>Before Monday&#8217;s class</em>, read the resource on <a href="http://kris.shaffermusic.com/musicianship/meter.html">meter and time signatures</a>, focusing on compound meter. Bring the Kazez and Berkowitz books to class.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cycle 1 quiz and practice]]></title>
    <link href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/09/cycle-1-quiz-and-practice/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-19T09:03:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/09/cycle-1-quiz-and-practice</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Wednesday, Sept. 25, will be the Cycle I listening quiz. It will contain the following items, and you will be allowed the number of listenings indicated below for each example:</p>

<ul>
<li>solfège patterns (2 hearings each, first and last pitch provided)</li>
<li>interval ID (2 hearings each)</li>
<li>triad ID (2 hearings each)</li>
<li>rhythmic dictation (4 hearings, with count-off for the meter)</li>
<li>melodic dictation (5 hearings, with a key-establishing cadence and count-off for the meter)</li>
</ul>


<p>To prepare for this quiz, please review your labs and practice any areas that you struggled with (either lots of wrong answers, or too many listenings to get the correct ones). Interval and triad ID are most easily practiced on teoria.com. For melodic dictation, you can use the recorded melodies provided in the <strong>MUSI 1121 shared materials</strong> folder on Google Drive. There are no count-offs or key-establishing cadences, so you may want to provide yourself an extra hearing to get oriented. I have a key for these melodies, so you can stop by my office to review your progress.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meeting 7 assignment]]></title>
    <link href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/09/meeting-7-assignment/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-17T09:51:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/09/meeting-7-assignment</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Prepare for the Cycle I recitation on Monday, Sept. 23. (Sign up on my office door, N138, if you did not do so in class.)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meeting 6 assignment]]></title>
    <link href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/09/meeting-6-assignment/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-16T12:51:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/09/meeting-6-assignment</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Begin (or continue) work in preparation for the Cycle I recitation. It will take place on Monday, Sept. 23.</p>

<p>Bring staff paper to class on Wednesday for more dictation practice.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meeting 5 assignment]]></title>
    <link href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/09/meeting-5-assignment/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-10T15:08:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/09/meeting-5-assignment</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>For Thursday, Sept. 12, 9am</em>, please do the following:</p>

<ul>
<li>Do <a href="http://www.colorado.edu/music/courses/musc1121/1_2/index.html">lab assignment 1.2</a> (both the worksheet and audio files can be found at that page).</li>
</ul>


<p>Please bring the completed worksheet by my office (slide it under the door if I&#8217;m not around), or take a picture of your completed worksheet and email it to me. Bring the original to class on Monday.</p>

<p><strong><em>Before submitting your assignment, please re-affirm the honor code in writing somewhere on the worksheet:</em></strong></p>

<blockquote><p>I hereby reaffirm the CU honor code. [sign your name]</p></blockquote>

<p>Or, simply,</p>

<blockquote><p>IHRTCUHC. [sign your name]</p></blockquote>

<p>Also, note that this lab will be graded on accuracy (see syllabus). Based on lab 1.1, that should not be a problem, and it will give you a good idea where you stand in advance of Quiz 1 (Sept. 23). (See Cycle I guide for updated schedule.)</p>

<p>Some additional resources may be helpful for you, depending on the state of your understanding of these concepts from written theory. Consult them, as needed. You may consult any informational resources (unless, of course, you happen to come across an answer key) while working on the lab assignment (including re-watching the video), but you may not consult another person as you work out the answers.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://kris.shaffermusic.com/musicianship/Intervals.html">Intervals and dyads</a></li>
<li><a href="http://kris.shaffermusic.com/musicianship/triads.html">Triads and seventh chords</a></li>
<li>Clendinning &amp; Marvin (your written theory textbook), Chapters 6 (&#8220;Intervals&#8221;) and 7 (&#8220;Triads&#8221;)</li>
</ul>


<p>(My resources are about a third as long as Clendinning/Marvin.)</p>

<p><em>Please be sure to bring both the Berkowitz anthology and staff paper to class on Monday.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meeting 4 assignment]]></title>
    <link href="http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/09/meeting-4-assignment/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-06T09:41:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://CUTheory.github.com/auralskills1/2013/09/meeting-4-assignment</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>For Tuesday, Sept. 10, 8am</em>, please do the following:</p>

<ul>
<li>Read/watch my resource on <a href="http://kris.shaffermusic.com/musicianship/melodicDictationDemo.html">melodic dictation</a>.</li>
<li>Do <a href="http://www.colorado.edu/music/courses/musc1121/1_1/index.html">lab assignment 1.1</a> (both the worksheet and audio files can be found at that page).</li>
</ul>


<p>Please <em>watch the video first</em>, as it will help with the lab assignment. Also note the due date/time. I want to look at the results as I plan for Monday&#8217;s class, so we can make best use of our time, and I need them submitted early to do that. Please bring the completed worksheet by my office (slide it under the door if I&#8217;m not around), or take a picture of your completed worksheet and email it to me. Bring the original to class on Monday.</p>

<p><strong><em>Before submitting your assignment, please re-affirm the honor code in writing somewhere on the worksheet:</em></strong></p>

<blockquote><p>I hereby reaffirm the CU honor code. [sign your name]</p></blockquote>

<p>Or, simply,</p>

<blockquote><p>IHRTCUHC. [sign your name]</p></blockquote>

<p>Also, note that this lab will be graded on completeness, not accuracy (see syllabus). It will give us a baseline from which to work as we focus our efforts on the greatest problem areas (and prepare for subsequent, higher-stakes assignments).</p>

<p>Some additional resources may be helpful for you, depending on the state of your understanding of these concepts from written theory. Consult them, as needed. You may consult any informational resources (unless, of course, you happen to come across an answer key) while working on the lab assignment (including re-watching the video), but you may not consult another person as you work out the answers.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://kris.shaffermusic.com/musicianship/Intervals.html">Intervals and dyads</a></li>
<li><a href="http://kris.shaffermusic.com/musicianship/triads.html">Triads and seventh chords</a></li>
<li>Clendinning &amp; Marvin (your written theory textbook), Chapters 6 (&#8220;Intervals&#8221;) and 7 (&#8220;Triads&#8221;)</li>
</ul>


<p>(My resources are about a third as long as Clendinning/Marvin.)</p>

<p><em>Please be sure to bring the Berkowitz anthology to class on Wednesday.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
